<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title> on Richard Toner </title>
      <generator uri="https://gohugo.io">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://richardtoner.github.io/</link>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    
    
    <updated>Mon, 02 May 2016 19:40:49 BST</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>April 2016 Mixtape: How Not to Descend Stairs</title>
      <link>http://richardtoner.github.io/post/april-2016-mixtape-how-not-to-descend-stairs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2016 19:40:49 BST</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://richardtoner.github.io/post/april-2016-mixtape-how-not-to-descend-stairs/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;So this is the moment where my music geekery will become very apparent. I haven&amp;rsquo;t written too much about music apart from the little &amp;ldquo;Like List&amp;rdquo; features at the end of my first few posts. However, if it wasn&amp;rsquo;t obvious already - &lt;strong&gt;I bloody adore music&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post is a first attempt to make something more of a longstanding tradition I have in creating &amp;ldquo;Monthly Mixtapes&amp;rdquo;. Obviously these aren&amp;rsquo;t cassette tapes, but I&amp;rsquo;m rather old-fashioned and think it sounds more romantic than &amp;ldquo;Monthly Spotify Playlists&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with most music-related traditions, thar be rules:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Only 1 song per artist per month.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A song cannot already be featured in a past monthly mixtape.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The run-time of the mixtape must be around 2 hours in length (I originally tried 90 minutes to remain in-keeping with the old cassette tape run times, but that was damn near impossible to cut down).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is my 34th monthly mixtape, so I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing this for a pretty long time now! I do find it a lot of fun though and love how it acts as a musical autobiography to my life. Even if I revisit the first set of mixtapes I created back in summer 2013, I can picture specific events from that summer clearly when I hear certain songs. It&amp;rsquo;s almost like a time capsule and helps underline the magic of a well-loved mixtape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So without further ado, let&amp;rsquo;s get stuck in to this month&amp;rsquo;s edition!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;34-how-not-to-descend-stairs:65a2fdcd2132cedce7317ef14337dbb7&#34;&gt;#34 How Not To Descend Stairs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The purpose of the mixtape title is to give me a clear personal snapshot of the month. This months title is related to me stacking it down a set of stairs in a London Underground tube station while trying to demonstrate to my sister how quickly I can descend a set of stairs&amp;hellip; We were out that day in support of my cousin&amp;rsquo;s husband running the London marathon, and he ended up in better shape than me! Anyway, it resulted in a visit to A&amp;amp;E and me walking at about half my normal pace for the rest of the month. Plenty of time to digest a lot more music then!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This month kicked off with one of the most insane release days ever on April 1st, as we saw new releases from Explosions in the Sky, Mogwai, Three Trapped Tigers and Hammock. I&amp;rsquo;m still reeling a bit from that day and haven&amp;rsquo;t given Three Trapped Tigers or Hammock anywhere near enough attention due to the strength of the recent O&amp;rsquo;Brother, Deftones and Explosions in the Sky albums.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also got teased some new tracks from the forthcoming Astronautalis and Thrice albums, which has raised the hype to boiling point for those releases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This month boasted some pretty spectacular gigs in London with Maybeshewill&amp;rsquo;s farewell show at KOKO, yndi halda at Hackney&amp;rsquo;s Oslo and Explosions in the Sky playing in the ever-beautiful Royal Albert Hall. Foxing also did a great job of seeing out the month with a very intense set at The Dome in Tufnell Park.&lt;/p&gt;


  &lt;iframe
    src=&#34;https://embed.spotify.com/?uri=spotify%3auser%3athetonerizor%3aplaylist%3a0Zz4tOb7toMWsP4NG3CXSo&#34;
    width=&#34;250&#34;
    height=&#34;330&#34;
    frameborder=&#34;0&#34;
    allowtransparency=&#34;true&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/iframe&gt;



&lt;h2 id=&#34;five-in-focus:65a2fdcd2132cedce7317ef14337dbb7&#34;&gt;Five in Focus&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this section I plan to delve deeper in to some of the choice cuts from the monthly mixtape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-heart-of-the-matter-by-young-in-the-city:65a2fdcd2132cedce7317ef14337dbb7&#34;&gt;1. &amp;ldquo;Heart of the Matter&amp;rdquo; by Young in the City&lt;/h3&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://richardtoner.github.io/images/april-2016-mixtape-how-not-to-descend-stairs/young-in-the-city-artwork.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Young in the City Artwork&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;It seems that everything Noah Gundersen touches at the moment turns to gold. Young in the City is his latest project, a rock and roll band based in his hometown of Seattle, Washington. The story is that Gundersen and some old high school bandmates decided to jam again for fun and see if the old songs were any good. They weren&amp;rsquo;t, so they went and wrote some new ones! The output of those jam sessions is the fantastic 4 song self-titled EP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Heart of the Matter&amp;rdquo; showcases instrumentation that feels as though it was plucked directly out from the American rock scene of the 80s. Despite the retro aesthetic, it manages to feel fresh in the same way that Lost in the Dream by The War on Drugs did back in 2014. I&amp;rsquo;m very excited by the possibility of Young in the City producing a full length album in the future, so I hope this is only a taste of the greatness that is yet to come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-the-logical-song-by-supertramp:65a2fdcd2132cedce7317ef14337dbb7&#34;&gt;2. &amp;ldquo;The Logical Song&amp;rdquo; by Supertramp&lt;/h3&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://richardtoner.github.io/images/april-2016-mixtape-how-not-to-descend-stairs/supertramp-breakfast-in-america-artwork.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Supertramp - Breakfast in America Artwork&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;There are certain songs that I will always associate with family holidays, and &amp;ldquo;The Logical Song&amp;rdquo; by Supertramp is one of the best of the bunch. When the sax solo hits I am immediately transported to the sun-soaked drives down the beach-front in Limassol, Cyprus and air-saxing away in the back of the car with my sisters. It&amp;rsquo;s a strangely vivid memory and I can even remember us all shrieking along to the final &amp;ldquo;WHO I AAAAAAAMMMM&amp;rdquo; line in an unbearably inaccurate falsetto that would cause my Dad to take his hands off the steering wheel just so that he could cover his ears.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is strange to listen to &amp;ldquo;The Logical Song&amp;rdquo; now as an adult and actually pick it apart, as it is the first time I have been blown away by the instrumentation. There are a total of 14 instruments used in the recording and each of them can be easily identified. Whether it&amp;rsquo;s the clacking of the castanets in the intro, the organ singing away in the background of the second verse, or the wah-wah clavinet on the outro. They all feel exceptionally well placed and add an extra layer of complexity to the song&amp;rsquo;s arrangement that prevents it from ever getting old.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thoroughly enjoyed reading more about the recording process of the song in this &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.soundonsound.com/sos/jul05/articles/classictracks.htm&#34;&gt;2005 article from Sound on Sound&lt;/a&gt;. Check it out and revel in the fact that such an iconic sax solo was actually recorded from the comforts of a toilet!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-bloodlines-by-o-brother:65a2fdcd2132cedce7317ef14337dbb7&#34;&gt;3. &amp;ldquo;Bloodlines&amp;rdquo; by O&amp;rsquo;Brother&lt;/h3&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://richardtoner.github.io/images/april-2016-mixtape-how-not-to-descend-stairs/obrother-endless-light-artwork.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;O&amp;#39;Brother - Endless Light Artwork&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;If O&amp;rsquo;Brother vocalist Tanner Merritt were to choose one song to include in a portfolio that showcases his vocal talents, then &amp;ldquo;Bloodlines&amp;rdquo; would be that song. In &amp;ldquo;Bloodlines&amp;rdquo; Merritt effortlessly switches between multiple vocal styles with eerie introductory choral chants, vibrato-laden verses, a subdued and haunting falsetto in the bridge, a frenzied outburst of throat-tearing screams and then forceful howling on the closing section that channels the combustible dynamic of Dustin Kensrue&amp;rsquo;s performances in Thrice&amp;rsquo;s Fire EP from The Alchemy Index.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Endless Light is the album that instantly turned me in to an O&amp;rsquo;Brother fan. This comes after years of failing to really get beneath the surface of their previous work barring a couple of remarkable songs off their debut EP. The mood set by the instrumentation is one of relentless impending doom and to say it feels like a soundtrack to the end of the world is an understatement. It feels as though the music reaches beyond that in its bleakness and could swallow entire solar systems by the time it reaches its conclusion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;4-stay-lost-by-joe-hertz-featuring-amber-simone:65a2fdcd2132cedce7317ef14337dbb7&#34;&gt;4. &amp;ldquo;Stay Lost&amp;rdquo; by Joe Hertz featuring Amber-Simone&lt;/h3&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://richardtoner.github.io/images/april-2016-mixtape-how-not-to-descend-stairs/joe-hertz-stay-lost-artwork.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Joe Hertz - Stay Lost Artwork&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s hard to see anything but superstardom ahead for London based producer Joe Hertz. All of his singles to date have been perfect 10s. He has a very distinct and infectious sound that always prompts the following conversation with anyone who hears his music for the first time:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Person Who Isn&amp;rsquo;t Me:&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ldquo;Who is this?&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Me:&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ldquo;Joe Hertz. Why?&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Person Who Isn&amp;rsquo;t Me:&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ldquo;This is bloody fantastic.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hertz also has a knack for picking outstanding guest vocalists. Amber-Simone is probably the pick of the bunch, with her smooth vocals spreading over Hertz&amp;rsquo; pristine production like Lurpak (that&amp;rsquo;s a very good thing - that stuff is heaven). Hertz has been active for a number of years, but we&amp;rsquo;re still eagerly awaiting an announcement of a debut EP / LP. I imagine that when that time rolls around it won&amp;rsquo;t be long before he is a household name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;5-hold-nothing-back-by-copeland:65a2fdcd2132cedce7317ef14337dbb7&#34;&gt;5. &amp;ldquo;Hold Nothing Back&amp;rdquo; by Copeland&lt;/h3&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://richardtoner.github.io/images/april-2016-mixtape-how-not-to-descend-stairs/copeland-in-motion-artwork.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Copeland - In Motion Artwork&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s amazing to think I&amp;rsquo;ve been listening to Copeland now for over a decade. They have such a incredibly strong back catalogue, but my personal highlight is 2005&amp;rsquo;s In Motion, their most aggressive and forceful release to date. Despite most of the appeal drawing from the louder portions of the album, the acoustic closing track &amp;ldquo;Hold Nothing Back&amp;rdquo; is the one that has stuck with me the most over the last 10 years. It is akin to a lullaby in its simple beauty and has some of the most gorgeous acoustic guitar melodies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently listened to a &lt;a href=&#34;http://noisecreators.com/2016/04/15/noise-creators-podcast-episode-032-greg-dunn-moving-mountains-prawn-dryjacket/&#34;&gt;Noise Creators podcast&lt;/a&gt; featuring producer / musician Greg Dunn of Moving Mountains. I&amp;rsquo;m really enjoying these podcasts at the moment, but something stood out to me in this podcast as Dunn discussed how he always aims to capture the organic and natural elements of a performance by leaving in the imperfections. These imperfections include little things such as the scratching of a string as the guitar slides from one chord formation to the other, or even the squeak of a drum stool as the drummer shifts his weight before beginning a performance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although Dunn did not work on Copeland&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Hold Nothing Back&amp;rdquo;, this song is a superb example of how the deliberate presence of imperfections can help transport you to a specific place and time. There are birds chirping, faint conversations in the distance and the stunning guitar work littered with fret buzz and the scratching of strings. If you close your eyes, you could almost picture yourself sat in a park near a busking Aaron Marsh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;lyric-of-the-month:65a2fdcd2132cedce7317ef14337dbb7&#34;&gt;Lyric of the Month&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;A smile can only bend so far before it breaks&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;
- &amp;ldquo;Happy Birthday&amp;rdquo; by Tiny Moving Parts&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-like-list:65a2fdcd2132cedce7317ef14337dbb7&#34;&gt;The Like List&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It feels odd to follow on from an entire post of things I like, to talk about more things I like&amp;hellip; However, I&amp;rsquo;ll keep it short and sweet and just touch on the one thing that needs a big up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;games-rogue-legacy:65a2fdcd2132cedce7317ef14337dbb7&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Games:&lt;/strong&gt; Rogue Legacy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve continued in the self-destructive pattern of failing to play games I already own and instead buying new ones at full price&amp;hellip; I have very few regrets for this one though, as Rogue Legacy is an absolute blast. It is a roguelike platformer, where a character death is permanent. The twist is that you can restart the game as a descendent of the previous character, inheriting their wealth and upgrades to give you an element of progression. You have a choice of 3 descendents which differ in classes and character traits to one another. These traits can range from beneficial, to puzzling, to downright hilarious. Here are a few examples:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ADHD:&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ldquo;So energetic! You move faster.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Color Blind:&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ldquo;You can&amp;rsquo;t see colors because of monochromacy.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I.B.S:&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ldquo;Even the most valiant heroes can suffer from irritable bowels.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve currently defeated 2 of the 5 bosses and have died 92 times. I think I&amp;rsquo;m doing pretty terribly, but I can&amp;rsquo;t get enough of the game and am already scoping out other roguelikes such as Spelunky and The Binding of Isaac for when I finish up Rogue Legacy. Check it out in the trailer below for Xbox One:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/CadrrGo3Au8&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boxen to Brew</title>
      <link>http://richardtoner.github.io/post/boxen-to-brew/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2016 11:30:26 BST</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://richardtoner.github.io/post/boxen-to-brew/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;automate-all-the-things:1e57fddae3a8b07c0cbe5040cedf66da&#34;&gt;Automate All The Things!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the most painful tasks in development can be configuring a workstation by hand. It&amp;rsquo;s funny how reading this back seems utterly ridiculous, yet little over a year ago this is exactly what I was doing. This became more complex and time consuming as our development team grew in size, so we decided to sort it out in a few key steps:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All developers to use the same workstations (MacBook Pros).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All workstations to be kept up-to-date with the latest OS X releases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All dependencies for company projects to be installed using Boxen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-s-in-the-boxen:1e57fddae3a8b07c0cbe5040cedf66da&#34;&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s in the Boxen!?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/boxen/our-boxen#our-boxen&#34;&gt;Boxen&lt;/a&gt; is an open-source tool for automating and managing Macs. It was developed by GitHub, primarily as a tool for themselves to get new starters up and running in about 30 minutes with a single command.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We first adopted Boxen in early 2015, but it has been kicking around since &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/blog/1345-introducing-boxen&#34;&gt;February 2013 when it was open sourced&lt;/a&gt;. It proved to be exactly what we needed to align our workstations, and we found it easy enough to customise using Puppet for our own project and personal manifests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first few uses were magical. It felt so good to just run a single command and come back 30 minutes later to a fully configured workstation. However, the cracks began to show as new versions of OS X were introduced. With so many dependencies on so many open source Puppet modules, it was inevitable that some of these dependencies would be less supported than others. The builds began failing and I found myself spending more time fixing Boxen than enjoying the benefits of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It also didn&amp;rsquo;t inspire confidence to allow my team to keep using a tool that &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/boxen/our-boxen/issues/783&#34;&gt;even the maintainers had abandoned ship on&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://richardtoner.github.io/images/boxen-to-brew/whats-in-the-box.gif&#34; alt=&#34;What&amp;#39;s in the Box(en)!?&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;It was time for a change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;boxen-be-gone:1e57fddae3a8b07c0cbe5040cedf66da&#34;&gt;Boxen Be Gone!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were no obvious contenders to replace Boxen when I first began the hunt for an alternative. It was only when I took a step back and looked at the component parts of Boxen that I realised I was already sitting on a potential replacement. Boxen uses &lt;a href=&#34;http://brew.sh/&#34;&gt;Homebrew&lt;/a&gt; as its primary package manager and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://caskroom.github.io/&#34;&gt;Homebrew Cask&lt;/a&gt; extension for most application installations. Although Puppet was the conductor, orchestrating all of the configuration tasks, it seemed like Homebrew and Homebrew Cask were the ones doing the heavy lifting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I found me a brand new conductor in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Homebrew/homebrew-bundle&#34;&gt;Homebrew Bundle&lt;/a&gt; extension.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Homebrew Bundle allows you to create a Brewfile, where you can list all of your dependencies, and just requires you to run a single command to get Homebrew to go and download them all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once I had our replacement lined up, it was time to bid farewell to Boxen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;nuke:1e57fddae3a8b07c0cbe5040cedf66da&#34;&gt;Nuke&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s best to take a note of anything that was installed by Boxen and use this to distinguish which packages and applications you’ll need when you make the jump to Homebrew.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To uninstall (almost) everything Boxen-related you need to run the following in your terminal:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ cd /opt/boxen/repo; ./script/nuke —all —force
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amazingly the flags &lt;code&gt;—all&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;—force&lt;/code&gt; don’t actually remove everything that was installed by Boxen so you may have to go sniffing around for any leftovers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;something-tasty-is-brewing:1e57fddae3a8b07c0cbe5040cedf66da&#34;&gt;Something Tasty Is Brewing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember that bit where I said you should take note of anything that was installed by Boxen? This is where that comes in handy! My list of requirements as a web developer was as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Atom&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bash completions for Git / Vagrant&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Git&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MySQL Workbench&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Node 0.12&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vagrant&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;VirtualBox&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next step is to translate this list in to a Brewfile. This is essentially a list of Homebrew commands, so you can easily work these out by just reading up on how you would individually install each of these packages. Here is what my list translates to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;tap &#39;caskroom/cask&#39;
tap &#39;homebrew/completions&#39;
brew &#39;bash-completion&#39;
brew &#39;git&#39;
brew &#39;homebrew/completions/vagrant-completion&#39;
brew &#39;homebrew/versions/node012&#39;
cask &#39;atom&#39;
cask &#39;mysqlworkbench&#39;
cask &#39;vagrant&#39;
cask &#39;virtualbox&#39;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be able to run this file we need to first install Homebrew and the Homebrew Bundle extension, which can be done by running the following in your terminal:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ /usr/bin/ruby -e &amp;quot;$(curl -fsSL https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Homebrew/install/master/install)&amp;quot;
$ brew tap Homebrew/bundle
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You then just need to navigate to the directory that your Brewfile is sitting in and run:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ brew bundle
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s it! Everything in your Brewfile should be installed and you&amp;rsquo;re up and running on a new development workstation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;mo-automation-mo-fun:1e57fddae3a8b07c0cbe5040cedf66da&#34;&gt;Mo&amp;rsquo; Automation, Mo&amp;rsquo; Fun&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Brewfile I created above serves more as a personal manifest than a project based one, so the next step is to create a Brewfile for each project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also remove a few of the manual tasks by rolling all of those terminal commands in to a shell script, much like what I&amp;rsquo;ve done with my &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/richardtoner/dotfiles/blob/master/bin/setup&#34;&gt;setup script in my personal dotfiles repository&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This approach has worked wonders for our development team in the last few months and installation times on new workstations are as little as a couple of minutes, as we avoid installing all of the additional packages and applications that Boxen enforced by default.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is also incredibly rewarding to know that any new dependencies will be installed without having to cross my fingers that Boxen will be able to cope. Homebrew always copes, and that fact alone makes Homebrew a winner in my books.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-like-list:1e57fddae3a8b07c0cbe5040cedf66da&#34;&gt;The Like List&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;food-rossa-pistachio-gelato:1e57fddae3a8b07c0cbe5040cedf66da&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Food:&lt;/strong&gt; Rossa Pistachio Gelato&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My newfound obsession with pistachio flavoured ice cream has drifted in to dangerous territory with the discovery of Rossa&amp;rsquo;s pistachio gelato&amp;hellip; Our local Spar supermarket in Walthamstow stocks it and it may very well be the eighth wonder of the world. Their website unfortunately isn&amp;rsquo;t the most informative in listing stockists, but if you like pistachio ice cream then my hyperbole should be enough to encourage you to sniff it out! Find out more over at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rossaicecream.com/&#34;&gt;www.rossaicecream.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://richardtoner.github.io/images/boxen-to-brew/rossa-gelato.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Rossa Gelato&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;h3 id=&#34;music-the-menzingers-on-the-impossible-past:1e57fddae3a8b07c0cbe5040cedf66da&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Music:&lt;/strong&gt; The Menzingers - On The Impossible Past&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m still a bit confused by how I&amp;rsquo;ve slept on this album for the last 4 years. &lt;a href=&#34;http://absolutepunk.net/&#34;&gt;Absolutepunk.net&lt;/a&gt; is undoubtedly my most-visited music website and this album was given the highest praise by being announced as the staff&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.absolutepunk.net/showthread.php?t=2971122&#34;&gt;#1 album of 2012&lt;/a&gt;. It is deserving of that praise as well, as it is a glorious nostalgia-tinged collection of punk anthems that go against the grain of conventional song structures and vocal deliveries. See what all the fuss is about for yourself by hitting play below:&lt;/p&gt;


  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://embed.spotify.com/?uri=spotify%3aalbum%3a4Jh3PDPicP3QwWpktQS7Yh&#34; width=&#34;250&#34; height=&#34;80&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowtransparency=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;



&lt;h3 id=&#34;travel-st-george-s-gardens-london:1e57fddae3a8b07c0cbe5040cedf66da&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Travel:&lt;/strong&gt; St George&amp;rsquo;s Gardens, London&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2002 Time Out magazine declared St George&amp;rsquo;s Gardens one of London&amp;rsquo;s best kept secrets. It is now 2016 and it is still one of London&amp;rsquo;s best kept secrets. I altered my commute to work to try and introduce some green space on my walk from Kings Cross to Holborn, and this is certainly the highlight of my morning. It is only small, but it makes up for size with beauty, especially when you catch it on a sunny morning. Find it &lt;a href=&#34;https://goo.gl/maps/XWF6BeWSKtM2&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://richardtoner.github.io/images/boxen-to-brew/st-georges-gardens-london.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;St George&amp;#39;s Gardens&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ready... Set... Hugo!</title>
      <link>http://richardtoner.github.io/post/ready-set-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2016 00:15:04 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://richardtoner.github.io/post/ready-set-hugo/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;an-introduction-of-sorts:aa937d473fc8d63545e4ed2103db6bf2&#34;&gt;An Introduction of Sorts&amp;hellip;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hi! This is my first post and I have already hit the backspace key more times than I have in the whole of 2016 put together&amp;hellip; I can tell this is going to be a bit interesting (or really time consuming).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The intention of this website is to act as a place for me to ramble on about the things that I like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I like &lt;strong&gt;code&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I like &lt;strong&gt;food&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I like &lt;strong&gt;games&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I like &lt;strong&gt;lists&lt;/strong&gt; (especially alphabetically ordered ones like this one)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I like &lt;strong&gt;movies&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I like &lt;strong&gt;music&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I like &lt;strong&gt;travel&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this being the first post, I&amp;rsquo;ll be dipping into the first one in that list and talk a bit about how I made this website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;hugo:aa937d473fc8d63545e4ed2103db6bf2&#34;&gt;Hugo!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This website is made using &lt;a href=&#34;http://gethugo.io&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was first introduced to Hugo a few months back when I was checking out the personal website of a very promising applicant to join our development team at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.snapfashion.co.uk&#34;&gt;Snap Fashion&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;m always interested in seeing what tools developers use to build their personal websites, as I feel that it is a big indication of what interests them the most. There was something about her website that inspired me to want to do the same for myself - so credit where credit is due: Thanks &lt;a href=&#34;https://purplebooth.co.uk&#34;&gt;PurpleBooth&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;hugo-1:aa937d473fc8d63545e4ed2103db6bf2&#34;&gt;Hugo?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hugo is a general-purpose website framework. Technically speaking, Hugo is a static site generator. Unlike other systems which dynamically build a page every time a visitor requests one, Hugo does the building when you create your content. Since websites are viewed far more often than they are edited, Hugo is optimized for website viewing while providing a great writing experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash; &lt;cite&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://gethugo.io/overview/introduction/#what-is-hugo&#34;&gt;The Brainy Bunch Behind Hugo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sounds cool, right? It is. And it is ridiculously easy to pick up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;getting-started:aa937d473fc8d63545e4ed2103db6bf2&#34;&gt;Getting Started&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://gethugo.io/overview/quickstart&#34;&gt;Hugo docs&lt;/a&gt; have everything you need to get started, but I&amp;rsquo;ll talk through what I did to show you exactly how easy it was for me to get to the point of publishing this post on a live website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;step-1-installation:aa937d473fc8d63545e4ed2103db6bf2&#34;&gt;Step 1: Installation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I installed with Homebrew by running:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ brew update &amp;amp;&amp;amp; brew install hugo
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;step-2-create-a-site:aa937d473fc8d63545e4ed2103db6bf2&#34;&gt;Step 2: Create a Site&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could then create the skeleton for a new website by running:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ hugo new site ~/Sites/my-hugo-website
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;step-3-create-a-new-post:aa937d473fc8d63545e4ed2103db6bf2&#34;&gt;Step 3: Create a New Post&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After navigating to my new website directory I created a new post by running:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ hugo new post/ready-set-hugo.md
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s less than a minute of effort and I was already writing content for a brand new website!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;step-4-pick-a-theme:aa937d473fc8d63545e4ed2103db6bf2&#34;&gt;Step 4: Pick a Theme&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Hugo website has a wide variety of themes available on &lt;a href=&#34;http://themes.gohugo.io&#34;&gt;themes.gethugo.io&lt;/a&gt;. I decided to go with the &lt;a href=&#34;http://themes.gohugo.io/hugo-uno&#34;&gt;Hugo Uno&lt;/a&gt; theme for starters, which I grabbed from Github by running:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ git clone git@github.com:SenjinDarashiva/hugo-uno.git ./themes/hugo-uno
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;step-5-have-a-peek:aa937d473fc8d63545e4ed2103db6bf2&#34;&gt;Step 5: Have a Peek&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a theme installed I could then run Hugo server to take a look at my brand spanking new website by running:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ hugo server --theme=hugo-uno --buildDrafts
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This command compiles the drafts and then hosts the website locally on an unused port. Hugo will tell you what web address you can visit to access your website once it finishes compiling (which is near instantaneous).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Behold!&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://richardtoner.github.io/images/ready-set-hugo/hugo-website-preview.png&#34; alt=&#34;My glorious work in progress!&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;h3 id=&#34;step-6-hugo-s-watching-you-wazowski-always-watching:aa937d473fc8d63545e4ed2103db6bf2&#34;&gt;Step 6: Hugo&amp;rsquo;s Watching You Wazowski&amp;hellip; Always Watching&amp;hellip;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the Hugo server up and running I kept editing this post, and Hugo simply kept an eye out for any updates, automatically compiling any new changes and instantly showing them to me within my web browser like magic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;step-7-hit-publish:aa937d473fc8d63545e4ed2103db6bf2&#34;&gt;Step 7: Hit Publish&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I finished up writing I then published the blog post by running:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ hugo undraft content/post/ready-set-hugo.md
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;step-8-configure-it-out:aa937d473fc8d63545e4ed2103db6bf2&#34;&gt;Step 8: Configure It Out&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the blog post was dated, published and ready to put live! Before putting the website live though I wanted to replace all that default stuff such as the site name, description and URL with my own stuff. All this required was for me to open up the &lt;code&gt;config.toml&lt;/code&gt; file in the base directory and populate it with the following information:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;baseurl = &amp;quot;http://richardtoner.github.io&amp;quot;
languageCode = &amp;quot;en-gb&amp;quot;
title = &amp;quot;Richard Toner&amp;quot;

[params]
  description = &amp;quot;A Welshy in London&amp;quot;
  author = &amp;quot;Richard Toner&amp;quot;
  github = &amp;quot;richardtoner&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also changed the default background image by adding an image to &lt;code&gt;./images/background-cover.jpg&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To see what other default stuff you can change, just take a look at the theme&amp;rsquo;s README.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;step-9-my-generation:aa937d473fc8d63545e4ed2103db6bf2&#34;&gt;Step 9: My Generation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only Hugo-shaped thing left to do at this point was to generate the static content, which I did by running:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ hugo --theme=hugo-uno
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;step-10-put-it-somewhere-people-can-see-it:aa937d473fc8d63545e4ed2103db6bf2&#34;&gt;Step 10: Put It Somewhere People Can See It&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The command I ran in the last step placed all the static content in &lt;code&gt;./public&lt;/code&gt;, so I just needed to plop the contents of the directory somewhere where people could see it. I personally chose to host it on &lt;a href=&#34;https://pages.github.com/&#34;&gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt;, which was as easy as committing all of the public directory contents to my &lt;code&gt;richardtoner.github.io&lt;/code&gt; repository and pushing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary:aa937d473fc8d63545e4ed2103db6bf2&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hugo is a breeze to get up and running with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found it refreshing to approach a new website implementation and having to dedicate very little thought at the technical implementation and design. The majority of my focus has been on &lt;strong&gt;the content&lt;/strong&gt;, which is the most important facet of a website of this nature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I plan to explore some of the more advanced features of Hugo soon. I will undoubtedly want to customise this theme or create my own, so I&amp;rsquo;ll probably describe that process in a future blog post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you got this far - thanks for reading my first ever blog post! Hopefully this will be the first of many!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-like-list:aa937d473fc8d63545e4ed2103db6bf2&#34;&gt;The Like List&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So this little section is directly inspired by Ryan O&amp;rsquo;Neal aka &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sleepingatlast.com&#34;&gt;Sleeping At Last&lt;/a&gt;, a brilliant and prolific musician from Illinois who has nailed down the art of a good newsletter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ryan runs a conceptual music subscription service called &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Atlas&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;, where he releases a song every few weeks complete with individual digital artwork, lyrics and the story behind the writing process of each song. He signs off each email with a list of the things he currently loves, and I look forward to it with each email. We have a great cross-over of interests, but the list also acts as a time capsule that I think serves purpose to him as well as his fans as a reminder of what he was surrounded by at the time of putting together that piece of art. I don&amp;rsquo;t really consider this post to be a piece of art, but I bloody love a good list!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here it is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;food-olia-hercules:aa937d473fc8d63545e4ed2103db6bf2&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Food:&lt;/strong&gt; Olia Hercules&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A highly talented Ukrainian chef with a love for everything fermented. We were fortunate to attend her event &lt;strong&gt;Fermented &amp;amp; Wild&lt;/strong&gt;, a celebration feast of fermented food and natural wines. I would not be surprised if they organised more of these in the future, so it&amp;rsquo;s worth giving her a follow on Instagram and keeping your eyes peeled if you&amp;rsquo;re privy to pickles!&lt;/p&gt;


  &lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;6&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAAGFBMVEUiIiI9PT0eHh4gIB4hIBkcHBwcHBwcHBydr+JQAAAACHRSTlMABA4YHyQsM5jtaMwAAADfSURBVDjL7ZVBEgMhCAQBAf//42xcNbpAqakcM0ftUmFAAIBE81IqBJdS3lS6zs3bIpB9WED3YYXFPmHRfT8sgyrCP1x8uEUxLMzNWElFOYCV6mHWWwMzdPEKHlhLw7NWJqkHc4uIZphavDzA2JPzUDsBZziNae2S6owH8xPmX8G7zzgKEOPUoYHvGz1TBCxMkd3kwNVbU0gKHkx+iZILf77IofhrY1nYFnB/lQPb79drWOyJVa/DAvg9B/rLB4cC+Nqgdz/TvBbBnr6GBReqn/nRmDgaQEej7WhonozjF+Y2I/fZou/qAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BCkte9bFKqy/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Olia Hercules (@oliahercules)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-03-05T13:49:08+00:00&#34;&gt;Mar 5, 2016 at 5:49am PST&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;



&lt;h3 id=&#34;games-rocket-league:aa937d473fc8d63545e4ed2103db6bf2&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Games:&lt;/strong&gt; Rocket League&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember that episode of Top Gear where they played football with cars and it looked like the best thing ever? Well if you throw in some insane physics, a spherical bomb and turbo-powered cars, you are left with Rocket League. It is as awesome as it sounds. Check out the madness in the video below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/2C9LxNlzeUM&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;music-yndi-halda-under-summer:aa937d473fc8d63545e4ed2103db6bf2&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Music:&lt;/strong&gt; yndi halda - Under Summer&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The wait is over! The long-awaited sophomore release from yndi halda has been 10 years in the making and holds true to the theory that good things come to those that wait. Under Summer is an hour-long musical journey over 4 tracks of beautiful introspective movements that swell to tidal wave-like crescendos. Prepare to get swept away and hit play on the Spotify player below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://embed.spotify.com/?uri=spotify%3aalbum%3a0ECiAUBuKpQ6sKaKUFFtlu&#34; width=&#34;250&#34; height=&#34;80&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowtransparency=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;travel-bristol:aa937d473fc8d63545e4ed2103db6bf2&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Travel:&lt;/strong&gt; Bristol&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What better way to enjoy an album that you&amp;rsquo;ve been anticipating for a decade than to take a walk through the city that you first remember falling in love with the band? Bristol has carved a very special place in my heart from the University days, and it was great to experience something so new in a place so familiar.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
