<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Thrice on Richard Toner </title>
      <generator uri="https://gohugo.io">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://richardtoner.github.io/tags/thrice/</link>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    
    
    <updated>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 19:11:13 BST</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>June 2016 Mixtape: The Long Defeat</title>
      <link>http://richardtoner.github.io/post/june-2016-mixtape-the-long-defeat/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 19:11:13 BST</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://richardtoner.github.io/post/june-2016-mixtape-the-long-defeat/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;35-the-long-defeat:0f5a3de131caf1d630f9d0c0e69354f6&#34;&gt;#35 The Long Defeat&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This month celebrates finding joy in even the harshest of defeats.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The joy that followed the defeat was Glastonbury Music Festival. With all the political and financial fallout following the EU referendum, it was a great source of escapism and proved once again that music unites us all and provides happiness in even the saddest of scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Glastonbury is always a huge source of music discovery for me and although I have never attended the festival, I feel perfectly satisfied with spending the whole weekend mud-free on my sofa and spending countless hours with the extensive BBC coverage. It also means I don&amp;rsquo;t suffer from FOMO at being there and being faced with 5 great acts clashing with one another!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Glastonbury was so late in the month that many of the artists I enjoyed do not feature on this playlist. However, expect to see a lot of these featured next month as I delve deeper into the back catalogues of M83, Grimes and Tame Impala.&lt;/p&gt;


  &lt;iframe
    src=&#34;https://embed.spotify.com/?uri=spotify%3auser%3athetonerizor%3aplaylist%3a0ADh2PNXte2RXaHoyNcaDf&#34;
    width=&#34;250&#34;
    height=&#34;330&#34;
    frameborder=&#34;0&#34;
    allowtransparency=&#34;true&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/iframe&gt;



&lt;h2 id=&#34;five-in-focus:0f5a3de131caf1d630f9d0c0e69354f6&#34;&gt;Five in Focus&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-the-long-defeat-by-thrice:0f5a3de131caf1d630f9d0c0e69354f6&#34;&gt;1. &amp;ldquo;The Long Defeat&amp;rdquo; by Thrice&lt;/h3&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://richardtoner.github.io/images/june-2016-mixtape-the-long-defeat/thrice-to-be-everywhere-is-to-be-nowhere-artwork.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Thrice - To Be Everywhere Is To Be Nowhere Artwork&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I was initially sceptical about championing a band two months in a row for the Five in Focus, but if any band is deserving of breaking a few rules for it is Thrice. &amp;ldquo;The Long Defeat&amp;rdquo; is an incredibly powerful cut from the bands latest album, &amp;ldquo;To Be Everywhere is to Be Nowhere&amp;rdquo; and felt like a natural selection for this months playlist due to the lyrical content from vocalist Dustin Kensrue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kensrue describes a world where deterioration is a tyrannical force that hinders any sense of progress. However, he promotes hope and togetherness in tackling the increasingly bleak future, as he underlines his belief that &amp;ldquo;there&amp;rsquo;s a way through the fire&amp;rdquo; and that &amp;ldquo;it&amp;rsquo;s ever bright beyond this black&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On &amp;ldquo;The Long Defeat&amp;rdquo;, Kensrue draws inspiration from the Christian and fantasy writer, J.R.R. Tolkien, repurposing many of his lines and even lifting the song title from Tolkien&amp;rsquo;s masterpiece, &amp;ldquo;The Lord of the Rings&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The concept of &lt;em&gt;the long defeat&lt;/em&gt; can be applied to the potential fate of humanity as a whole, or even as reference to our individual mortality. We are all destined to pass away when it is our time, but Kensrue&amp;rsquo;s belief that there&amp;rsquo;s a &amp;ldquo;joy that blooms beyond these walls&amp;rdquo; could be interpreted as a declaration of hope that there is an afterlife that will provide warmth, brightness and relief from the suffering of the world we currently inhabit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However you choose to interpret &amp;ldquo;The Long Defeat&amp;rdquo;, it is the message of hope that stands tallest as Kensrue exits wearily, yet unwavered in his repetition that &amp;ldquo;together we&amp;rsquo;ll fight the long defeat&amp;rdquo;. In these times of political uncertainty, we need songs like this more than ever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-solstice-by-if-these-trees-could-talk:0f5a3de131caf1d630f9d0c0e69354f6&#34;&gt;2. &amp;ldquo;Solstice&amp;rdquo; by If These Trees Could Talk&lt;/h3&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://richardtoner.github.io/images/june-2016-mixtape-the-long-defeat/if-these-trees-could-talk-the-bones-of-a-dying-world-artwork.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;If These Trees Could Talk - The Bones of a Dying World Artwork&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Bones of a Dying World&amp;rdquo; is the new album by If These Trees Could Talk and serves as my introduction to a band that seemingly should need no introduction to anyone familiar with the post-rock genre. Nevertheless this seems a great place to start as the album is outstanding and sits shoulder to shoulder with releases from Russian Circles and Pelican as the finest in the post-metal scene.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Solstice&amp;rdquo; is the first track off the album and juggles both beauty and brawn in equal measure. The shimmering reverb-laden guitar work provides the gorgeous backbone of the song which repeatedly gets one of its vertebrae smashed out from underneath itself each time the drums and distorted guitars thunder in for a metallic passage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the song reaches its conclusion you are yearning for the journey to continue, which speaks volumes of the strength of the album as a cohesive whole. I can see the album etching an even more visceral connection with myself in the darker, colder months to come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-tilted-by-christine-and-the-queens:0f5a3de131caf1d630f9d0c0e69354f6&#34;&gt;3. &amp;ldquo;Tilted&amp;rdquo; by Christine and the Queens&lt;/h3&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://richardtoner.github.io/images/june-2016-mixtape-the-long-defeat/christine-and-the-queens-chaleur-humaine-artwork.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Christine and the Queens - Chauleur Humaine Artwork&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The highlight of Glastonbury festival for me this time around was French singer-songwriter Héloïse Letissier, or Christine and the Queens as she prefers to go by as her stage name. I was initially drawn in by her minimalistic private performance of &amp;ldquo;Tilted&amp;rdquo; for the BBC highlights show, with Letissier showing off her bizarre Michael Jackson-esque dance moves while flexing her impressive mixed language vocals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was hungry to see more and then watched her full set on The Other Stage, which was a mesmerising blend of theatricality and tour-de-force vocals. There were numerous standout songs in the set, but &amp;ldquo;Tilted&amp;rdquo; proved to be the most infectious and the perfect introduction to an artist that has a blindingly bright future ahead of her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;4-palm-dreams-by-touché-amoré:0f5a3de131caf1d630f9d0c0e69354f6&#34;&gt;4. &amp;ldquo;Palm Dreams&amp;rdquo; by Touché Amoré&lt;/h3&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://richardtoner.github.io/images/june-2016-mixtape-the-long-defeat/touche-amore-stage-four-artwork.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Touché Amoré - Stage Four Artwork&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;This is a very promising taster from the forthcoming Touché Amoré album, &amp;ldquo;Stage Four&amp;rdquo;. Touché Amoré began to lean towards a more melodic sound on &amp;ldquo;Is Survived By&amp;rdquo;, but &amp;ldquo;Palm Dreams&amp;rdquo; deviates even further from their past work with the introduction of clean backing vocals and crystal-clear production. Everything sounds less abrasive than it once was for the band, and I can&amp;rsquo;t help but think this song neatly fills the void left behind by Alexisonfire, especially when that lead guitar lick comes in at the 0:45 second mark.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jeremy Bolm is often revered as one of the best lyricists in rock music and is never afraid to open himself up wholly in his songs. On &amp;ldquo;Palm Dreams&amp;rdquo;, Bolm is at his most vulnerable as he details the pain of clearing out his mother&amp;rsquo;s old family home in the wake of her passing. The song forms a tornado of grief and regret, as he raises questions surrounding the possessions of his late mother that will forever remain unanswered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is something about the subject of a death in the family that allows a song or album to connect with me in a way that other subjects cannot. Although I have not suffered much loss within my own family, it is perhaps the inevitability of those losses that allows me to place myself in those songs and be stirred so convincingly by them. In recent years, albums from Pianos Become the Teeth, The Hotelier and Sufjan Stevens explored loss in their own ways and are now some of my most treasured albums. I don&amp;rsquo;t know if I can expect the same kind of connection with &amp;ldquo;Stage Four&amp;rdquo;, but if &amp;ldquo;Palm Dreams&amp;rdquo; is a sign of things to come then this may be one of the most important releases of the year for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;5-the-coast-by-pup:0f5a3de131caf1d630f9d0c0e69354f6&#34;&gt;5. &amp;ldquo;The Coast&amp;rdquo; by PUP&lt;/h3&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://richardtoner.github.io/images/june-2016-mixtape-the-long-defeat/pup-the-dream-is-over-artwork.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;PUP - The Dream is Over Artwork&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;PUP possess a special strain of self-deprecation, with their band name being an acronym for Pointless Use of Potential and their sophomore album being titled &amp;ldquo;The Dream is Over&amp;rdquo;, directly paraphrasing a doctor who told vocalist, Stefan Babcock, that he would never sing again after shredding his vocal cords. However, &amp;ldquo;The Dream is Over&amp;rdquo; has been met with such resounding critical acclaim that suggest the dream is far from over. In fact, PUP seem to just be getting started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Coast&amp;rdquo; is one of the more melodic songs on the album, something that might be difficult to believe when Babcock rips into a throat-tearing series of screams on the chorus:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Now you know what&amp;rsquo;s eating me!&lt;br&gt;
Taking hold!&lt;br&gt;
It was dragging me down!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The aggression is pointed firmly at a frozen lake in Canada that has claimed the lives of a number of its townsfolk during the spring and summer melt. Babcock treats the lake as a living entity, explaining how it &amp;ldquo;needs to eat like all living things and it&amp;rsquo;s hungriest in the spring&amp;rdquo;. It is detailed with such menace and character that it almost feels as though the lake is an antagonist in a horror movie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They close out the chaos with a morose passage that is so unsettling that it had to be included below as my lyric of the month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;lyrics-of-the-month:0f5a3de131caf1d630f9d0c0e69354f6&#34;&gt;Lyrics of the Month&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;A little girl has gone missing.&lt;br&gt;
Has anyone heard she&amp;rsquo;d gone out to go fishing?&lt;br&gt;
The cracks in the ice make a mighty fine grave in the summer thaw.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;- &amp;ldquo;The Coast&amp;rdquo; by PUP&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-like-list:0f5a3de131caf1d630f9d0c0e69354f6&#34;&gt;The Like List&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;travel-madrid:0f5a3de131caf1d630f9d0c0e69354f6&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Travel:&lt;/strong&gt; Madrid&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s always highly enjoyable to visit a foreign city for a second time. It feels as though there is less pressure to cram as much as you can in to your visit and that you can just enjoy the feeling of being back in a city that you loved so much that it warranted a second visit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I first visited Madrid back in 2011, so the city still felt very familiar to me. We decided to spend our weekend avoiding the museums and popular sights and instead spent a long afternoon in the gorgeous Retiro park and browsing the various markets around the city. It is such a lively and well loved city and demonstrates all that is beautiful about the Spanish way of life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://richardtoner.github.io/images/june-2016-mixtape-the-long-defeat/madrid-retiro-park.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Madrid - Retiro Park&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time to start planning a third visit I think&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>May 2016 Mixtape: Old Habits Made New</title>
      <link>http://richardtoner.github.io/post/may-2016-mixtape-old-habits-made-new/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2016 22:51:18 BST</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://richardtoner.github.io/post/may-2016-mixtape-old-habits-made-new/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;35-old-habits-made-new:63e4854d895b857b2a7fddbfcad8eb55&#34;&gt;#35 Old Habits Made New&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This month celebrates a welcome return to old habits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A number of years ago I used to treat all new music releases as something that would require my full and undivided attention. I would simply lie down on my bed with the accompanying booklet in hand and read the lyrics or appreciate the artwork, with no other distractions. I suppose that habit fizzled out as a result of the gradual decline of the physical medium for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I started my Spotify premium subscription back in 2012, I tend not to buy any physical releases until I have listened to them and assessed whether they are worth owning. Most of my first listens now take place during my commute to work, where you lose that magic of devoting your full attention to a release that you&amp;rsquo;ve been anticipating for months. Despite Spotify giving me the opportunity to discover and try so much music, I am connecting with albums a lot less than I did when I purchased a handful of them a month and gave them all the time they deserved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to change it up this month with two of the most important releases in recent memory for me, with new albums from The Hotelier and Thrice. I did not purchase them, but I decided to be patient and avoid listening to them on release day, so that I could devote time to each release over the weekend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent Saturday lying down on my bed listening to the new Thrice album with all the windows open and the cold air blowing through the room, and I enjoyed it so much that I played it through twice. I gave The Hotelier a slightly different treatment and opted to switch my phone off and go for a walk in the forest as the sun began to set. Both experiences have left huge lasting impressions on me and I feel that for the first time in a very long time that I am able to remember what I was doing and how I was feeling the first time that I connected with a new album.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It feels great to escape the daily grind every now and again and I am excited to turn this old habit in to something new as I explore a whole new horizon of music.&lt;/p&gt;


  &lt;iframe
    src=&#34;https://embed.spotify.com/?uri=spotify%3auser%3athetonerizor%3aplaylist%3a0ADh2PNXte2RXaHoyNcaDf&#34;
    width=&#34;250&#34;
    height=&#34;330&#34;
    frameborder=&#34;0&#34;
    allowtransparency=&#34;true&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/iframe&gt;



&lt;h2 id=&#34;five-in-focus:63e4854d895b857b2a7fddbfcad8eb55&#34;&gt;Five in Focus&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-geneva-by-russian-circles:63e4854d895b857b2a7fddbfcad8eb55&#34;&gt;1. &amp;ldquo;Geneva&amp;rdquo; by Russian Circles&lt;/h3&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://richardtoner.github.io/images/may-2016-mixtape-old-habits-made-new/russian-circles-geneva-artwork.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Russian Circles - Geneva Artwork&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Nearly everyone I know who has heard Russian Circles refers to them as the band that could soundtrack the end of the world. &amp;ldquo;Geneva&amp;rdquo; is an excellent example of this, as it sounds as though it is lifted directly from a disaster movie. The opening 2 minutes play out like a pursuit, with a menacing and steady build until the guitars break in to a gallop and you can feel the pace quicken. The chaos then unfolds as the cymbals come crashing in and the guitars begin to swirl around in distort, placing you in the eye of the storm. As the instruments begin to dissipate one by one, you feel as though you catch your breath for a few seconds. Then Brian Cook introduces that huge stabbing bassline at the 02:22 mark, which wields enough power to be capable of trepanation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Geneva&amp;rdquo; is an absolute leviathan of a song. Witnessing this live at dunk!festival was an unforgettable moment, and one of the many reasons why Russian Circles were my top pick of the festival. I am now waiting eagerly for their new album &amp;ldquo;Guidance&amp;rdquo;, which is due for release on August 5th.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-dizzy-by-jimmy-eat-world:63e4854d895b857b2a7fddbfcad8eb55&#34;&gt;2. &amp;ldquo;Dizzy&amp;rdquo; by Jimmy Eat World&lt;/h3&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://richardtoner.github.io/images/may-2016-mixtape-old-habits-made-new/jimmy-eat-world-chase-this-light-artwork.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Jimmy Eat World - Chase This Light Artwork&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;At the start of the month chorus.fm published an article entitled &lt;a href=&#34;https://forum.chorus.fm/threads/the-ultimate-jimmy-eat-world-setlist.2619/&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Ultimate Jimmy Eat World Setlist&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;. It was a highly enjoyable read that celebrated the exceptional discography of Jimmy Eat World, attempting to squeeze the best songs for a live performance setting in to an 80 minute playlist. Any fan of Jimmy Eat World will appreciate how difficult this is and somehow the author Craig Ismaili was able to do this in a way that satisfied most members of the chorus.fm community, including myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve still yet to make my own version of the playlist, but &amp;ldquo;Dizzy&amp;rdquo; would undoubtedly be deserving of a place. It is a triumphant song that soars in both a live and recorded setting and boasts some of the greatest lyrics Jim Adkins has ever put to paper. I can no more than justify the reason for its placement by copying Craig Isimaili in quoting the bridge:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I told you as I hovered, &amp;ldquo;I’ve never felt this way.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br&gt;
You said, &amp;ldquo;I have the shot that stops my clock, baby its okay.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br&gt;
You said you’d never have regrets.&lt;br&gt;
Jesus, is there someone yet who got that wish?&lt;br&gt;
Did you get yours, babe?&amp;rdquo;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;- &amp;ldquo;Dizzy&amp;rdquo; by Jimmy Eat World&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-piano-player-by-the-hotelier:63e4854d895b857b2a7fddbfcad8eb55&#34;&gt;3. &amp;ldquo;Piano Player&amp;rdquo; by The Hotelier&lt;/h3&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://richardtoner.github.io/images/may-2016-mixtape-old-habits-made-new/the-hotelier-goodness-artwork.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;The Hotelier - Goodness Artwork&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Piano Player&amp;rdquo; was the first song to be teased from The Hotelier&amp;rsquo;s new album, &amp;ldquo;Goodness&amp;rdquo;. I initially met it with trepidation, confused by their decision to let the vocals sit so low in the mix, as I consider the vocals and lyrics of Christian Holden to be the component that make their 2014 album, &amp;ldquo;Home, Like Noplace is There&amp;rdquo;, one of my all-time favourite albums.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Holden penned an open letter a few months back addressing the fans and telling them to listen to &amp;ldquo;Goodness&amp;rdquo; with an entirely open mind. &amp;ldquo;Goodness&amp;rdquo; is a celebratory record of love and life, it is not an extension of the cathartic &amp;ldquo;Home, Like Noplace is There&amp;rdquo;, and nor should it be. &amp;ldquo;Home&amp;rdquo; was an exorcism that has led The Hotelier in to an entirely new and positive phase of their lives that I am more than happy to join them in as a fan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took Holden&amp;rsquo;s advice and listened to &amp;ldquo;Goodness&amp;rdquo; for the first time without the weight of any expectation and an entirely open mind. I decided to go for a walk in Epping Forest without any direction in mind and switched off all mobile communication. It was a beautiful 47 minutes and the album felt like a natural companion to the stunning views of the evening sun-soaked forest with birds flying overhead and wild flowers in bloom. I believe it is how The Hotelier had intended most people to experience the album, and I&amp;rsquo;m glad that I took the time to do so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is far too early to tell what I think of the album as a whole, but I am already excited to listen again and feel this will serve as a fitting soundtrack to the wonderful summer months ahead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;4-salt-and-shadow-by-thrice:63e4854d895b857b2a7fddbfcad8eb55&#34;&gt;4. &amp;ldquo;Salt and Shadow&amp;rdquo; by Thrice&lt;/h3&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://richardtoner.github.io/images/may-2016-mixtape-old-habits-made-new/thrice-to-be-everywhere-is-to-be-nowhere-artwork.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Thrice - To Be Everywhere Is To Be Nowhere Artwork&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;There is no better feeling than when an album lives up to the hype. After hearing &amp;ldquo;Blood in the Sand&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Black Honey&amp;rdquo; and watching a few of the in-studio videos, I felt primed for the new album and decided to ignore any more teasers and just wait patiently for the full album. It was worth the wait.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hiatus has been nothing if not kind to Thrice. I still consider them to be one of my favourite bands, but I had admittedly lost a lot of interest in them with &amp;ldquo;Beggars&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Major/Minor&amp;rdquo;, and didn&amp;rsquo;t greet their hiatus with much sadness as I felt that we had already seen the best of Thrice. This new album has proved that theory wrong, as this boasts some of the best songs they&amp;rsquo;ve ever written.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Salt and Shadow&amp;rdquo; is one of those songs. It acts as a stunning closing track that epitomises the album title of &amp;ldquo;To Be Everywhere Is To Be Nowhere&amp;rdquo; with its lyrical content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;On the edge of a knife, it&amp;rsquo;s like you&amp;rsquo;re living your life on the stage.&lt;br&gt;
You&amp;rsquo;re talking through glass, we&amp;rsquo;re just square photographs on a page.&lt;br&gt;
Oh, we&amp;rsquo;re never alone but we&amp;rsquo;re each in our own little cage.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;- &amp;ldquo;Salt and Shadow&amp;rdquo; by Thrice&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lyrics paint a picture of a person who is living in the &amp;ldquo;everywhere&amp;rdquo; of the Internet through their mobile device, rather than being present in the now with those that they are physically with. They are more concerned with broadcasting their lives to others and embracing the celebrity status that they feel in sharing their lives with the world. It is a poignant and thought-provoking song that weaves nicely with my own feelings towards technological ubiquity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;5-just-another-face-by-modern-baseball:63e4854d895b857b2a7fddbfcad8eb55&#34;&gt;5. &amp;ldquo;Just Another Face&amp;rdquo; by Modern Baseball&lt;/h3&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://richardtoner.github.io/images/may-2016-mixtape-old-habits-made-new/modern-baseball-holy-ghost-artwork.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Modern Baseball - Holy Ghost Artwork&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I feel as though I have finally got rid of that horrible habit of feeling that certain artists are &amp;ldquo;guilty pleasures&amp;rdquo;. This has affected my enjoyment of so many talented artists, as I did not give them the attention they deserved (see Paramore, Lorde and Linkin Park). Modern Baseball were strangely one of those bands that I considered to be a guilty pleasure, simply because they wrote playful lyrics and appeal to a teenage fanbase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It genuinely surprised me when I reached the end of 2014 and found that their album &amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;re Gonna Miss It All&amp;rdquo; was one of my most played of the year. It helped me move past that perception of Modern Baseball being a band I shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be allowed to enjoy, as I obviously enjoyed it to the point where I played it more than the majority of albums that made my top 10 that year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This paved the way for me to feel genuine excitement for the next entry in the Modern Baseball discography, hungry for more hooks and humourous barbs pointed at themselves and others. However, there is no more watching Planet Earth and brainstorming tattoos on &amp;ldquo;Holy Ghost&amp;rdquo;. Just as I had grown up with my acceptance of the fun side of Modern Baseball, they&amp;rsquo;ve done a lot growing up themselves as they battle with adulthood. Jacob Ewald helps underline this fact when he sings &amp;ldquo;There will be no more fucking around today&amp;rdquo; on the third track &amp;ldquo;Note to Self&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Holy Ghost&amp;rdquo; is a very personal record for the 2 songwriters / vocalists, Jacob Ewald and Brendan Lukens, with them exploring themes of loss, loneliness and mental illness. It hits a lot harder too when you watch their documentary, &amp;ldquo;Tripping in the Dark&amp;rdquo;, which tells us how Ewald lost his Grandfather and how Lukens came close to ending his life as a result of his depression and social anxiety.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/PApxRlpvsIU&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;With all of the emotion running through &amp;ldquo;Holy Ghost&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Just Another Face&amp;rdquo; makes for an incredibly powerful closing song. The self-deprecation is present in the verses as it was in Lukens&amp;rsquo; songs on &amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;re Gonna Miss It All&amp;rdquo;, but it holds a lot more weight here and cannot be taken lightly when Lukens sings &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m a waste of time and space&amp;rdquo; with utter conviction and exhaustion. He sounds all but ready to throw in the towel until he signals the sudden need for change with a rallying cry that leads in to the spectacular chorus. The lyrics in the chorus are resoundingly supportive and provide not just a glimmer, but a beacon of light for Lukens and anyone else who suffers from mental illness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;lyrics-of-the-month:63e4854d895b857b2a7fddbfcad8eb55&#34;&gt;Lyrics of the Month&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After all that praise for the lyrical content of &amp;ldquo;Just Another Face&amp;rdquo;, it&amp;rsquo;d be odd for me not to champion those lyrics as the best of the month!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;If it&amp;rsquo;s all the same, it&amp;rsquo;s time to confront this face to face.&lt;br&gt;
I&amp;rsquo;ll be with you the whole way. It&amp;rsquo;ll take time. That&amp;rsquo;s fact.&lt;br&gt;
I&amp;rsquo;m not just another face. I&amp;rsquo;m not just another name.&lt;br&gt;
Even if you can&amp;rsquo;t see it now, we&amp;rsquo;re proud of what&amp;rsquo;s to come, and you.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;- &amp;ldquo;Just Another Face&amp;rdquo; by Modern Baseball&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-like-list:63e4854d895b857b2a7fddbfcad8eb55&#34;&gt;The Like List&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;games-doom:63e4854d895b857b2a7fddbfcad8eb55&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Games:&lt;/strong&gt; DOOM&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel very fortunate to have been a kid during the advent of the DOOM franchise. DOOM was my first ever first-person shooter, and I don&amp;rsquo;t doubt that I would&amp;rsquo;ve been forced to take it back to the shops if it weren&amp;rsquo;t for the fact that my Dad loved it so much while assessing whether it was appropriate, that he decided that we had better hold on to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last DOOM game I played was DOOM 3 back in 2004, which was a pretty forgettable experience for me as it leaned towards the slower survival horror genre and away from the berserk pace of the original DOOM games. This new DOOM release crept up on me, and it was only when the tube stations were littered with images of revenants and DOOM guys that the hype fully kicked in and it rendered me a gormless victim of advertising as I bought it outright on release day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Was it worth it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HELL YES.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m only a handful of levels in at the moment, but this is more than I ever could have expected from a franchise that has been dormant for 12 years. It is an absolute blast, and the environments and monsters are all utterly terrifying while equally beautiful to stare at. Just don&amp;rsquo;t stare too long at the monsters or you may end up being a victim of an encounter like my one with the revenant in the video below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hint: they&amp;rsquo;re not very nice as far as monsters go&amp;hellip;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/llau2LK2OlY&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
